如兄弟寄托妻子儿女或重要事件
When a brother entrusts his family to you,
不尽心竭力者 不得好死
those who fail will die a horrible death.
不得好死
Die a horrible death.
兄弟钱财物件 须有借有还
Respect each other's property and pay your debts.
如有存心吞没者 生不如死
Offenders will face a fate worse than death.
生不如死
Face a fate worse than death.
不许搬弄是非 捏造事实
Don't spread vicious lies.
明知故犯者 死无葬身之地
Offenders will be fed to the dogs.
死无葬身之地
Fed to the dogs.
干嘛
What are you doing?
加入黑社会
Joining the Gang.
我是问你下面怎么啦
I mean down there.
我的纸内裤都湿透了
There's a hole in my paper underwear.
今后大家都是和义盛的兄弟了
From now on, you're brothers.
老大就是你爹 帮会就是你娘
The Don is your father, the Gang is your mother.
谁背叛爹娘天打雷劈
Traitors will be punished by death.
每人一个
Take one.
知不知道出来混
What's the key
最重要是甚么
for being a gangster?
是路
His path.
无缘无故的
No one...
谁会给条路你们走
will show you the path.
是你自己
You are on your own.
路是人走出来的
You have to find your own path.
我火水能从西环踩到上环靠的是甚么
How did I, Kerosene,
你们知不知道
expand my turf into Sheung Wan?
靠的是霸道 我这么霸道
By being overbearing.
上环的路哪够我走呀
But Sheung Wan is not big enough for me.
要走啊就得走大路
That's why I need to keep going.
你们今天叫我做大哥
Today, I'm your Boss.
以后这条大路就大家一起走
Together, we'll keep going.
上环不够走 就踩到中环
If Sheung Wan is not big enough, we'll take Central.
中环不够走 就踩到铜锣湾
If Central is not big enough, we'll take Causeway Bay.
老大开奔驰有甚么了不起
The Boss driving a Mercedes Benz is no big deal.
我要我的兄弟都开奔驰 那才了不起
I want all my men to drive a Mercedes Benz.
虽然你们今天吃面包
Today, we're eating bread.
但是我火水哥保证
But I guarantee...
迟早大家一齐吃顶级鲍鱼
you'll all be eating abalone soon.
那条纸内裤呢
Where's the paper underwear?
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
是刚才那只鸡
Is that from the initiation?
是
Yes.
怎么弄的
What did you do to it?
我把酒搽在鸡肉上
I rubbed wine on the chicken,
然后用叶子和泥巴把它包起来烧
wrapped it with a leaf and roasted it in the mud.
就是刚才用来遮住你下面的那片叶子
The same one you covered your dick with?
叶子是用来调味的
It's for the taste.
难怪有一股浓烈的虾酱味
No wonder it smells like shrimp paste.
谁教你的
Who taught you?
我们家是开大排档的
My family ran a food stand.
我五岁就学会弄鸡了
I knew how to cook a chicken when I was 5.
本来打算长大后自己开小菜馆
I wanted to open my own restaurant.
但我怕会像我爸那样要交保护费
But I didn't want to pay extortion like my old man
所以就来投靠火水哥你了
That's why I came to you.
是吗
Yeah?
是谁那么大胆敢收你保护费
Who had the balls to collect from you?
我派人阉了他
I'll have him castrated.
不就是火水哥你
You did.
有这回事
Really?
不过
Maybe...
也许这就是你我的缘份
it's our fate.
师傅曾经说过我这条命
Master said my life was destined
是"一将功成万骨枯"
to succeed over many dead bodies.
原来是虾酱的"酱"
Maybe he meant dead chickens.
对了
So...
你刚才说要开小菜馆
you want to open a restaurant?
是呀
Yes.
那你愿不愿意替我打江山
Will you fight for my turf?
试试看吧
I'll try.
好兄弟
Good.
你叫甚么名字
What's your name?
萧近南
RuPaul Siu.
萧近南这名字
RuPaul Siu?
多没气势怎出来混呀
That's lame.
那干脆就跟我姓火
You need more fire.
叫火脯
I'm naming you Roast Pork.
我火水哥今天就对火发誓
I, Kerosene, do solemnly swear.
如果有天我当上坐馆的话
When I become the Don,
有我火水的地盘
Roast Pork will open a restaurant
就有你火脯的鸡店好不好
in every district I run. Alright?
好
Alright.
Good?
好 好
Good. Great?
Geat. Alright?
好
Alright.
好兄弟
My man.
砍
Kill him.
砍死他
Kill.
老婆
Honey.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you.
请慢用 请慢用
别客气
Help yourselves.
干杯
Cheers.
没有没有呀
No.
二十一家分店我都问过了 没有呀
I checked all 21 stores. Nothing.
都满啦
They're all fully booked.
史提芬伯格又怎么样
Steven Spielberg? So what?
我最后一张桌都留给冯小刚导演啦
I saved the last table for Feng Xiaogang.
什么冯小刚都不认识
You don't know him?
你还拍什么电影呀
And you work in film?
史提芬呀
Hello, Steven.
到香港啦
You're in Hong Kong?
住四季是吧
The Four Seasons?
照旧点那些菜好
Same dishes? Alright.
半小时后到 谢谢 再见
30 minutes. Thank you, bye.
老婆怎么有空来帮忙啊
Honey, how nice of you to drop by.
是不是又看中了甚么名牌皮包
Saw something you like... a handbag?
难道我用你一万多也要你批准
Do I need your permission to spend 10 grand?
不是这个意思
That's not what I mean.
我的意思是
You only spent 10 grand
我老婆现在还用一万多的皮包
on a handbag.
这么节省不知道该如何报答你
How can I ever repay you for being so frugal?
这样吧 我们下星期去日本
Let's go to Japan next week
去看新店的装修
to check out our new shop,
顺便逛逛街
do some shopping,
再顺便看看有甚么漂亮皮包
check out the handbags,
再顺便我们
check out the...
要不要带萧立和萧玉一起去
I'm bringing the kids.
我们带着孩子去干什么
What for?
我们很久没过 "二人世界" 了
We need time to ourselves.
还有我上网查过
I checked on the internet.
有家时租酒店
There's this love motel
我们可以一边玩 一边拍录像
where we can film ourselves in the sack.
滚开
Get lost.
可你答应过孩子们
You promised to take the kids if they got accepted to the elite school.
考上名校 就带他们去日本玩的
To Japan if they got accepted to the elite school.
他们真的考上名校了 这么厉害
They did? That's awesome!
这些年一帆风顺
Things are going well.
说不定老大一开心
If the Boss agrees...
连那根龙头棍也让给我摸摸呢
I'd like to get my hands on the Dragon Head Baton.
你很想摸吗
You do?
老婆我开玩笑的
I'm just kidding.
开玩笑
Kidding?
你答应过我 不再碰社团的事
You promised to wash your hands on the Gang.
知道
Will do.
你先放手
Please let go.
你试试不开玩笑再说一次
I'd like to see you get serious about it.
再碰 我就是混蛋
I'm the asshole if I do that.
走啦
Leaving already? Thank you.
谢谢 谢谢 谢谢 走了
Thank you. Thank you.
炎先生签的卡 已经超过信用额了
You have exceeded your credit card limit, Mr. Yim.
两个豪宅 二次按揭 五期未还
5 installments behind on both of your second mortgages.
基金有四期未供 三份迷你债券到期
4 payments behind on your trust fund and 3 accumulators have matured.
根据条款 我们需要取消你的所有账户
I'm afraid we have to cut our account.
不过这样
But then again,
我们银行本着
true to our commitment to serve
植根香港服务社群的宗旨
the community,
我们诚意介绍一个
we'd like to offer you
债务重组计划给炎先生
Debt Relief Plan (DRP).
王经理
Mr. Wong.
你该知道我的背景吧
Do you know who I am?
知道知道
Of course.
炎方瑞先生是社团和义盛的领导人
You're the Don of the Gang.
你知道我是坐馆的
你怕我没钱还
you still think I can't pay my debts?
不怕不怕
Of course not.
不过根据资料显示
But according to our intelligence,
炎先生的任期还有几个星期就届满
your term is up in a few weeks.
没这回事
There's no such thing.
没事没事
It's alright.
不如这样 我们有两个债务重组计划
We can offer you two DRPs for your consideration.
想推荐给炎先生 我组你祖宗
DRP, my ass!
你信不信我找人砍死你 再把这银行给烧了
I can chop you to pieces and burn your bank.
信信
Of course you can.
首先 说要干掉我呢
About chopping me up,
我本人已经买了保险 但受益人不是你
I'm well insured, but you're not the beneficiary.
所以干掉我 对你的债务是于事无补的
Chopping me up won't help your situation.
其次就是 这家银行也买了保险
The bank is also well insured.
碰巧受益人也不是你
But again, you're not the beneficiary.
所以你烧了它
Burning it down won't help
对你的债务仍然是于事无补的
your situation.
以炎先生的现状来说
Judging from your situation,
你参加我们银行的破斧沉舟债务重组计划
you really should join our DRP...
你再说多一次
I dare you to say that again.
你扫掉我的东西
Trashing my desk
对你的债务还是于事无补的
won't help your situation either.
大哥甚么事
What is it, Boss?
没事这里是银行
Nothing. We're in a bank.
是是
Yes, yeah.
没事没事
It's alright.
大哥走吧
Let's go, Boss.
我不打你就不姓炎
I'll fix you or my name is not Kerosene.
何必恼火呢 都是于事无补呀
Getting upset still won't help your situation.
打死你这个王八蛋
You bastard.
这家银行就垮啦 赶快把钱提走吧
There'll be a run on the bank, get your money.
一路走好 炎先生
I'm sorry. Watch your step, Mr. Yim.
这是甚么世界
What has the world come to?
我拿一千万公款来做定期
I take out a time deposit of $10 million.
昨晚看新闻说
When I watched CNN last night,
宾夕凡尼亚州有家甚么小银行
a small bank in Pennsylvania went bankrupt
被一个卖色情片的老板把钱全提走
because a guy who sells pornography
那银行就马上倒闭
withdrew all his money.
社团的帐一向由我管理 我当然要小心
I keep the books for the Gang, I must be careful.
本想给它做个压力测试
I gave the bank a stress test
说要把钱都提出来
by withdrawing my money.
真不敢相信这么大的银行
Would you believe a bank of this size
这点压力也受不了
can't handle the pressure?
那混蛋听了之后被吓坏了 又跪又拜的
That sucker froze and went down on his knees to beg.
谈不拢 还反咬我一口
He started to make accusations.
我能不还手
I had to do something.
真他妈的
Damn.
我找人把它给烧了
I'll burn it to the ground.
大哥
Boss.
我刚才在银行全都听见了
I was there, I heard what happened.
如果确实有困难 你早说呀
Just tell me if you need help.
我没事
I'm fine.
这几年你当坐馆
You should have made a fortune
也应该捞不少
being the Don.
我捞个屁呀
From what?
代客泊车 才收二十块钱
You get a $20 tip for valet parking.
卖盗版 都被网络下载给打垮了
The pirated copies are screwed by BT.
那些吸毒的
The junkies have switched
都跑去吸五百元的 "自助餐"
to those $500 buffets.
好了 想退一步海阔天空
So I take a step back
去市场收保护费
and tried to extort money from the markets
那些老板 居然说以后把钱只交给政府
but the owners would rather pay the goνernment.
银行利息又低
Interest rates are low.
管帐 管帐 管到我这种地步
I'm screwed right and left.
当坐馆 火脯
Some Don I am.
一三五坐差馆
Police stations on odd days;
二四六坐殡仪馆
funeral homes on even days.
黑也管 白也管
真是名符其实的坐着被人管
I'm nothing but a sitting duck.
大哥
Boss.
不行的话 你别跟我客气
You can tell me.
钱我有
I have money.
你以为你是奥巴马
Who do you think you are? Obama?
我这个金融黑洞 你帮不了
You can't fix my financial black hole.
下一任坐馆 万一要是被别人当了
Let someone else take over.
我恐怕比陈水扁还倒霉
I wish, but I have worse luck than Chen Shui-bian.
不会
No.
你怎么跟他比呢
Of course not.
好啦 火脯你的心意 大哥知道
Thanks for the thought.
再说吧
We'll talk later.
大哥 你去哪
Where are you going?
走路回家
Home.
你的跑车呢
Where's your Lamborghini?
没开
Didn't drive it.
我打算参加国际马拉松
I intend to join the marathon.
今天还差十公里
I'm 10 km short today.
大哥
Boss.
其实你可以随便找几个兄弟先做一届
Find someone to take over the next term.
然后再让兄弟们慢慢把那笔帐填好
Let him sort out the money.
这样你不就没事了
And you'll be off the hook.
你说找谁做好呢
Who do you have in mind?
再想想
Let met think.
一起想
Let's do that.
招牌鸡
My signature chicken dish
不爱吃
No good?
不是
It's not that.
想起找谁当坐馆 顿时 没了胃口
Thinking of the next Don makes me lose my appetite.
想来想去 不知道找谁最合适
I can't think of anyone.
慢慢吃 吃饱再想
Don't think on an empty stomach.
我去看看老婆要不要帮忙
I'll check the stove.
不用了
Hey
被我刚刚想到
I got it.
谁啊
Who?
你呀
You.
开玩笑吧 大哥
You're kidding.
我不开玩笑 再说一次 好不好
I'll say it again, I'm not kidding.
别闹啦
Stop it
一三五差馆 二四六殡仪馆
Police stations on odd days, funeral homes on eνen days.
黑也管白也管 我有那么多店要管
坐馆 我真的做不来
I can't do it.
你还记得你有这么多店
So you still remember your restaurants?
是怎么来的
Where did they come from?
恭喜 恭喜 恭喜
Congratulations. Congratulations.
火脯 我那票一定投给你
You have my vote, Roast Pork.
火脯 我早就知道你是当坐馆的材料
I knew you're cut out for the job.
放心吧 火脯
Relax.
我们这帮老人家都商量好了
We had it all figured out.
到时候我们都会支持你当坐馆
You have our support.
选坐馆
We're electing the Don.
选都不选 造假呀
Is it fixed?
剪刀伟 什么时候轮到你说话
Scissors, you spoke out of turn.
我有本事 干嘛不能说话
Why? I have the balls.
伟哥说得对
He's right.
有能力就要表达
He has a right to speak up.
况且 伟哥天生就有一副坐馆相
He has the look of a Don
伟哥出马 谁敢不服
No one would object.
谁都可以 就是他做不得
Anyone can do it except him.
为甚么 剪刀伟确实一副坐馆相呀
Why? He has the look.
坐馆相这玩意见人见智
That's a matter of opinion.
最糟糕是所有和义盛里的人都知道
他身边的得力助手阿仁是卧底
his top thug Yan is an undercover cop.
就他不知道
Except him.
有这么白痴
How idiotic can he be?
说出来你也许不信这个阿仁
Believe it or not,
是一九八九年警察学校的一级荣誉学生
Yan was an honored cadet in 1989.
还没毕业就被反黑组警司刘华给挑中
Inspector Lau Wah recruited him before graduation
开始他的卧底生涯
to be an undercover agent.
从今天开始 你再不是二五六四一
From now on, you're no longer P.C.25641.
走
Go.
一年后 二五六四一进了和义盛门下
A year later, he came to us.
但他始终无法忘记自己的警察身份
But he can't seem to forget he's a cop.
结果他一次又一次的暴露身份
He blew his cover again and again.
简直不把我们和义盛放在眼里
This is so insulting.
看他不是阿仁吗
Look. There he is.
本来我们计划杀一敬百
We meant to kill him as a warning to all.
但查叔说多一事不如少一事
But Uncle Tsa preferred to let it slide.
没想到却有意外收获
And we were in for a pleasant surprise.
刘长官
Inspector.
有情报
Lobster Bay,
下星期六下午三点 龙虾湾
next Saturday at 15:00 hours.
那批毒品后来改在星期五晚上交易
The cocaine deal was rescheduled to Friday.
平安无事
It went without a hitch.
从此以后 有甚么大买卖
From then on, whenever there's a deal,
先漏些消息给他 让他引开警察
we feed him with disinformation to shake the cops.
来我们为新一届和义盛的坐馆干杯
Let's drink to the next Don.
来干杯 干杯 干一杯酒
Cheers.
火脯 过来
Roast Pork.
拿着
Congratulations.
来啊
Come.
当坐馆应该开心呀
You're the Don, look happy.
干呀
Drink up.
嫂子
Nancy.
今天是火脯上位掌管龙头棍
Roast Pork now holds the Dragon Head Baton.
你不是想跟他挣吧
You want to fight him for it?
孩子们怎办
What about the kids?
大哥
Boss.
刘长官带了一队人来查牌
Inspector Lau is here.
这么热闹
What a turnout.
谈好谁来当坐馆了吧
Have you chosen the next Don?
逮捕他
Arrest him.
收到
Yes, sir.
长官 干嘛要抓我
Why are you arresting me?
例行公事
Routine business, it happens to all the new Dons.
我们以前当坐馆的都是这样 辛苦了
Good luck.
刘长官 给点面子吧
Show me some good will, Inspector.
好歹也给个头罩戴上吧
At least give me a bag.
伙计 就给他个袋子
Officer, get him a bag.
出来了
Here they come.
后面那个 后面那个 长官 让他把头抬一下吗
Sir, would you mind if i take a photo?
害甚么羞 来啊
Don't be shy. Come on.
帅的
How cute.
还不睡啊
Still up?
给你两个孩子找学校呀
I need to find a school for the kids.
那名校不是录取他们了吗
I thought they were accepted into an elite school.
他们现在是和义盛的坐馆子女呀
But their father has become the Don!
还是这几家有经验 甚么东兴 洪英
These schools have more experience with the gangs.
他们坐馆的子女都在这里上学
Kids of other Dons go to this school.
正好他们有经验
They know what to do.
叫两个孩子尽快进去替你打天下
Send your kids there to start recruiting for you.
老婆
Honey.
你知道出来混最重要是甚么
What's the key to being a gangster?
是路
His path.
我出来混 是要把菜做好
I join the Gang because I want to cook,
因为我的子女要上名校
so my kids can go to an elite school,
因为我老婆可以用名牌
so my wife can buy brand label handbags.
火水今天不放一条生路给我走
If Kerosene won't leave me alone,
我也不会放活路给他
I won't give him peace either.
我要告诉他 这二十年来
I will show him
我不是白混的
I didn't spend my last 20 years doing nothing.
现在和义盛的抽屉底下穿了个大洞
The Gang is in the red.
水哥亏空了社团上千万
Kerosene embezzled $10 million.
我们唯一的办法
The only thing
就是把水哥揪出来
to do is finger him.
太晚了 我收到消息
It's too late.
说他想把那笔帐赖到了脯哥身上
He blamed the debt on Roast Pork,
说是用来替脯哥开菜馆
said he spent it on his restaurants.
没别的办法了
We haνe no way out
跟他拚吧
but to fight him.
怎么拚
How?
以前抢的当坐馆还没打够
People used to risk their lives to be the Don.
现在不想当坐馆又要打
Now you risk yours so you won't be the Don?
兄弟们谁还肯动手
Our guys won't do it
有没有联系过兄弟们
Did you contact them?
这几年大家跟着脯哥做正行
Like you, they have gone legit
都风生水起全上岸了
and made a fortune.
孤家寡人的只剩我们这几个
We're the only ones who are still single.
不到逼不得已 也不好意思打扰人家
It's best not to bother them.
就说毒品强
Junkie Keung
吸到二百多磅重
now weighs over 200 pounds.
还有最能打的红蕃
Even our top henchman Indian
去年都娶了儿媳妇了
got his son a wife last year.
怎么没请我喝喜酒
Why wasn't I invited?
有
You were.
他在骼骸头的店 请了五十多桌
He held a banquet for 600 at the Skull's restaurant.
那天你女儿发烧你没去
You didn't go because your son had a fever.
你们有替我给贺金吧
Did you give him a red packet for me?
有 替你给了八千八
I gave him $8,800.
谢谢
Thanks.
骼骸头 鱼翅有砂呀
The Skull? Their shark's fins stink.
当然啦 他还去跟无耻拿货
Because he bought them from Fouler.
无耻以前去买刀砍人还要吃回扣
Fouler took kick-backs even on our weapons.
照我说 买海产最好还是三四八
I think DJ has the best seafood.
识货 当然三四八
Indeed, DJ is the place.
他的鲍鱼都是糖心的
Their abalones are succulent.
那海参 质量更是没得说顶瓜瓜
Their sea cucumbers are superb.
说甚么海参鲍鱼呀
What's this bullshit with abalones and sea cucumbers?
还是说火水这件事
Let's get back to Kerosene.
你们还有甚么主意
Any ideas?
我查过了
I checked.
现在警察局有个甚么罪犯自新计划
The cops are offering a Clean Slate program for criminals.
你放甚么屁
That's bullshit.
不如这样
Well...
我们找水哥的结拜兄弟开山刀来谈一谈
Let's talk to Kerosene's sworn brother Quarry Knife.
反正他从小就占水哥便宜
He used to bully Kerosene when they were little.
但是这几年
Over the past few years
这家伙卖饭盒跟筷子给我们
the asshole made a fortune
都发了 还爱上了打高尔夫球
selling Styrofoam lunch boxes to us. He's hooked onto golf
天天打十八个洞
and plays his 18 holes eνery day.
水管那帮人就是跟他去打球的
Tube's men play with him.
自己拿了中港牌照 还开车上去呢
He drives to China with a HK-Chinese license.
现在拿个中港牌照要多少钱
How much does a HK-Chinese license cost?
找炮仗辉 二十万就搞定
Firecracker can get you one for 200 grand.
不行 炮杖辉搞的 只能走西部通道
No way, his is only good for the Western Corridor.
哪有皇岗二十四小时方便
Huanggang is open 24 hours. It's more conνenient.
要走当然走皇岗
Who'd take the Western Corridor?
怎会走西部通道呢 提起皇岗 提起皇岗
Speaking of Huanggang...
我们刚才提到的那帮兄弟
we were talking about the guys...
别说了干脆报警
Forget it, just call the cops.
老婆使不得
No, Honey.
我们这几年虽然赚到钱
We've been making money
但始终都是混帮会的
but we're triad members nonetheless.
水哥要我当坐馆
Kerosene wants me to be the Don.
他算得很绝
That's a shrewd move.
现在这局面就像 巴塞对南华
This is like Barcelona against South China,
受让一球
handicap 0:1
而且南华还少打两个
and South China is down 2 players.
输定了
We're doomed.
如果巴塞打假球不就行了
What if Barcelona rigs the game?
巴塞打假球会太明显吧
That's too obνious.
如果巴塞
What if...
被罚停赛又怎样
Barcelona is suspended?
小圈子选举
This is what we call small-circle election.
和义盛搞到今天这地步
The Gang is in the present predicament
问题根源就是假民主
fundamentally because of phony democracy.
大哥话可不能这样说
Not exactly, Boss.
根据警察总部档案室的资料
According to the Police file,
和义盛的选举制度是源自比例代表制
the Gang's election is based on proportional representation.
像查叔那一票
Take Uncle Tsa's vote for instance,
他就要向下面的二千三百六十五人负责
he must answer to the 2,365 men under him
而那二千三百六十五个人 大部份是来自走私及私油业界
and most of those 2,365 men smuggle petrol.
他们每月交钱给社团
They pay the Gang every month.
交出来的钱就像选票一样
The money they hand over is like a vote.
要是不满意代表的投票意向
If they're not happy with how Uncle Tsa votes,
他们会选择不交钱 而对代表进行罢免
they'll impeach him by refusing to pay up.
可以罢免的吗
He can be impeached?
那为甚么那些老家伙可以做那么久
Then why are those old goons still hanging around?
问题就出在这几年和义盛的生产总值
That's because the Gang's GNP
每年都有超过百分之三十的增长
has an annual growth rate of over 30%.
只要一直保持这样好的经济环境
As long as they keep it up,
就没人会过问那些老鬼在做甚么
nobody cares what they do.
所以
So
根本不是制度的问题
there's really nothing wrong with the system.
只怪兄弟们的公民意识实在太差
The guys simply have poor civic awareness.
如果可以在公民教育这方面下点苦功
We must do better on civic education...
阿仁
Yan.
我真的没看错你
I was right to trust you.
小意思
It was nothing.
在警察总部档案室
The Police file room
我留下不少脚毛
is my crash pad.
大哥我先听个电话
Boss, let me get this
喂
Hello.
明天晚上火脯会动手
Roast Pork will make a move tomorrow night.
他要放火烧大星银行
He'll burn down Star Bank.
你先等一下
Hold on.
位置是沙田坳道
On Shatin Col Road.
火脯要放火烧甚么
What is he burning?
火脯要放火烧大星银行
Star Bank.
你等一等 等一等
Hold on.
说吧 沙田坳道六十九号
Go on. 69 Shatin Col Road.
等一下沙田甚么道
Shatin what?
沙田坳道
Shatin Col Road.
"坳"字怎么写
How do you spell that?
你自己想吧
Go figure.
沙田坳道六十九号大星银行
Star Bank, 69 Shatin Col Road.
便利店斜对面金辉阁桑拿楼下
Across from 7-Eleven, under Glory Mansion,
邻近三号线巴士总站
next to the No. 3A bus terminal
附近还有转接港铁站的专线小巴
with shuttle buses connecting to the subway.
交通方便
Convenient location.
你让我进来就是看你撒尿
I'm not here to watch you.
走走走
Get lost...
走呀
Go.
大哥
Boss.
刚才你说在警察总部留下很多脚毛
The Police HQ is your crash pad?
甚么意思
What does that mean?
我是卧底嘛
I'm an undercover cop.
你是卧底
Undercover?
我是说我有卧底呀
I mean I planted an undercover
我放了自己人在警察局
inside the Police HQ.
怎么放
How?
这么容易告诉你 我的卧底岂不很危险
Can't say, it'll endanger my guy.
不说这些了
Forget it.
我有情报 火脯明晚去烧银行
I got wind Roast Pork will burn a bank.
如果火脯被警察抓住了
If he gets arrested,
除了大哥你
who but you
还有谁能上坐馆这个位子
is elegible to become the Don?
对呀
That's right.
沙田坳道六十九号大星银行
Star Bank, 69 Shatin Col Road.
便利店斜对面金辉阁桑拿楼下
Across from 7-Eleven under Glory Mansion,
邻近三号线巴士总站
next to the No. 3A bus terminal
附近还有转接港铁站专线小巴交通方便
with shuttle buses connecting to the subway. Convenient location.
老公 烧银行好大罪的
Burning a bank is a serious crime.
有多大罪
How serious?
在银行门外的水泥地上放火
I'm burning the cement outside the front door.
警察只能告我游荡行为不检
The cops can only charge me for loitering or misdemeanor.
进去坐一两个礼拜
I'll be sentenced to 2 weeks in jail.
到时候甚么馆都选完啦
When I get out, the election will be over.
听清楚别搞错
Get this straight.
是沙田道 不是沙田坳道
Shatin Road, not Shatin Col Road.
对 那银行在沙田道
Yes, the bank is on Shatin Road.
大哥
Boss.
老公
Honey.
没事的
I'll be fine.
警察十一点五十五分会巡逻到这里
The beat cop will be here at 11:55p.m.
你的手干吗
What's with your hand?
没有
Nothing.
我在打拍子
Counting the beat.
我不是问你在干吗
Not that
是问你的手怎么了
I mean your hand.
你不是弄伤右手的吗
I thought you injured your right hand.
这就是右手呀
This is my right hand.
你当我白痴啊 这只是右手
Am I stupid? That's your right hand?
这只呀
I mean this one.
是这只呀
This one.
你说清楚点嘛
Make yourself clear.
你是说你的右
You mean your right?
当然
Yes.
我以为你指的是我的右嘛
I thought you meant my right.
那我对不起了 是我不对
Sorry.
你的手这么久还没好
Your hand is taking too long to heal.
去看我的医生吧
Go see my doctor.
哪来的钱呀 你的医生太贵啦
How can I afford the medical fee?
傻瓜钱当然我来付
I'll pay for it, silly.
那怎么好意思
I can't do that.
甚么不好意思 我们是兄弟嘛
Why not? We're brothers.
整天跟我说客套话
Cut the civility crap.
我从小就没甚么朋友
I don't have any friends.
大家都嫌我笨
They all think I'm stupid.
我不就是没方向感嘛
I just don't have any sense of direction.
我老实跟你说
I'll be honest with you.
多年来
After all these years,
我还分不出左和右
I still can't tell right from left.
我有努力过
I tried
就是没人给我机会
but people won't give me a break.
到现在只有你不笑我
You're the only one who doesn't make fun of me.
我看得出来
I can tell.
我不知道你怎么想
I don't care what you think.
不过当作你是亲兄弟
You're my brother.
怎么了
What's wrong?
眼睛湿了
Why are your eyes tearing up?
很感动呀
Are you touched?
没有
No.
大哥
Boss.
其实当上坐馆
Becoming the Don
也没甚么了不起
is really no big deal.
你有没有想过改做正行
Have you thought of going straight?
我已经做正行很久啦
I already did.
我知道当坐馆这条路 很困难
I know the road to becoming the Don is tough.
不过就算天塌下来
No matter what shit happens,
我也会一个人撑住 它不会连累你
I'll deal with it. I won't get you in trouble.
也别说谁连累谁
Don't say that.
万一
If something
你有甚么事
happens to you,
我也可以替你作证
I'll testify for you
把你转做污点证人
and turn you into state witness.
甚么人
State what?
火水那帮人
Kerosene's men.
是啊
Right.
各单位准备
All units, stand by.
肚子饿了 先吃块饼干
I'm hungry.
不是吧 这样都行
How could you? Thanks.
很好吃啊
Not bad.
你别动
Freeze.
别动 把刀放下 把刀放下
Put the knife down. Put it down.
干嘛在街道撒尿 缩回去
Stop peeing. Stick it back in.
我叫你缩回去呀
Stick it back in.
行动
Action.
走 走 走
Go...
警察 都别动
Police. Freeze.
放下火 把手放在头上别动
Put down the torch, hands on your head.
别动 别动 别动
Don't move.
王八蛋
Asshole.
我知道 你为大哥甚么事都做得出来
I know you'll do anything for me.
但你记住 你从今天起就不一样了
But times have changed.
你就快当坐馆了 你知不知道
You'll be the next Don.
万一你有甚么事
If anything happens to you...
我这个做大哥的 一样可以为你赴汤蹈火
I'm capable of anything.
怎么啦 我说的话不合适
You don't like what I said?
不是
I do.
那就好
Good.
记住 要听话
You must behave.
人在风暴中无奈的打转
A man's twirling in the storm
如像风沙倦也须兜转
like the sand, without reprieve.
无奈的疾冲无奈的打转
A reluctant clash and slash turns a familiar face cold.
谁赞成火脯做应届和义盛的坐馆
Any objection to Roast Pork becoming the Don?
和义盛第十九... 等等
The 19th...
鸭梨姐 你搞甚么
Hold it. What is it, Pearl?
你们还记不记得
Don't you remember?
燕子回巢 奉为龙头
"The swallow will lead upon its return."
你是不是更年期迟了 抽甚么风
You have PMS? Return from what?
老查 这句话是你说的
You said it, Tsa.
是不是年纪大 全都忘了
You're too old to remember?
在坐的老头子 是不是都老人痴呆啦
You all have Alzheimer's?
恭喜文哥出狱
Congratulations, Swallow.
今天我的阿文出狱
My Baby gets out today.
你们是不是又说是一套 做又是另外一套啊
Do you know talk is cheap but action speaks volume?
你有病 你儿子都坐了二十年牢
Are you nuts? Your son has been in jail for 20 years.
别说担大旗 连智能卡他都不会用吧
He can't eνen use a credit card, let alone be the Don.
我的阿文不够资格担大旗
My Baby is not qualified?
掐死你也不难呀
He can turn you into minced meat.
二十年前阿文入狱
20 years ago, when my Baby went to jail,
你火水把阿文的三大弟子赶出市区
Kerosene evicted his thugs from the city.
没想到错有错着
The border regions have developed rapidly ever since.
迪卡比奥掌管十二条皇岗巴士线路
Di Caprio now owns 12 bus routes to Huanggang
载客量超过两万人
with a passenger traffic of over 20,000.
东涌仔垄断了东涌八成的装修搬运生意
Tung monopolized 80% of the renovation and moνing business in Tung Chung.
这二十年来 东涌的人口增长
Tung Chung's population increased
超过百分之四百三十
by 430% oνer the past 20 years.
打桩机 是屯门的淫业大亨
Rammer is now the king of pornography in Tuen Mun.
八成佳丽桑拿 一楼一凤 都归他管
He controls 80% of the hookers and massage parlors.
屯门的适龄黑社会人口
People in Tuen Mun of suitable age for the triad
占了全港百分之二十三
accounts for 23% of Hong Kong's population.
你们三个还没死啊
You assholes are still alive?
恭喜文哥出狱
Congratulations, Swallow.
大哥 外面那帮老头子在开会
Those old fogies are having a meeting.
火水推荐他的手下火脯当坐馆
Kerosene wants YMT district head Roast Pork to be the next Don.
我也想去油麻地走一趟
I want to go to YMT district.
好啊 大哥那里是火脯的地盘 你去干嘛
What for? That's Roast Pork's turf.
找点东西
I'm looking for something.
找家伙去我店里拿吧
You can take anything from my shop.
手枪 牛肉刀 手榴弹 甚么都有
Guns, knives, grenades... anything.
我要找的 那里才有
Only Yaumatei has what I want.
太棒了 甚么家伙我没有啊
Yes. What is it? Atomic bomb?
东涌 屯门 新界边境的发展一日千里
Tung Chung, Tuen Mun and the border region are growing fast.
他们三个加起来的人力和财力
Their wealth and manpower
足足有我们和义盛的一半
add up to half of the Gang.
谁敢说我的燕子文落伍了
Who said my Baby is passé?
还有 你们可别忘了
Don't forget
我鸭梨是燕子文的母亲
I'm his mother.
和义盛的开山祖师大刀王五是我亲爷爷
My Grandpa Iron Bodyguard founded the Gang.
这够不够资格担大旗 火水哥
He's definitely qualified. Right, Kerosene?
燕子文正杀向油麻地 直踩火脯的地盘
Swallow is heading for Yaumatei, straight to Roast Pork's turf.
油麻地集结了一千九百多人
1900 men have gathered.
一千九百多人 我报警
1900? I'm calling the cops.
你疯了 报警
Are you crazy?
黑社会报警 丢不丢人
You should be ashamed of yourself.
火脯 叫你的人马上走
Roast Pork, tell your men to back off.
不关我事 那些不是我的人
They're not mine.
那是我的人
They're mine.
大哥说过要挺你
I told you I'd back you up.
我再派一千人去
I'll send another 1000 men.
火水你别乱来 这样会坏大事
Take it easy, Kerosene.
鸭梨 燕子文那件事都过去二十年了
Pearl, that was 20 years ago.
现在香港都回归了
Hong Kong has reverted back to China.
谁当坐馆 该按特区选举条例
The Don must be elected according to the HKSAR election ordinance.
不是 应该按照帮规投票决定
I mean... we should go by the book, take a νote.
我投火脯
I vote for Roast Pork.
四对四
4 to 4.
江湖规矩
Gangster's rule.
跟我儿子打一场
Let them fight.
时间 地点 马上签约
Name the time and place. I'll sign.
不行
No.
燕子文到了油麻地
Swallow has arrived in Yaumatei.
你们谁想来挡我
You want to stop me?
找死啊你
You? Get them. Get lost...
自己人不打自己人
Don't fight your own.
告诉阿文 谁找到龙头棍 就谁当坐馆
Tell Swallow whoever finds the Dragon Head Baton will be the Don.
查叔 十几年前的反黑大行动
When the cops busted us over a decade ago,
连龙头棍也被缴去了
they took the Dragon Head Baton.
目前被放在警察博物馆里
It's still sitting in the Police museum.
找不到龙头棍 那找龙尾棍
Then find the Dragon Tail Baton.
你有病呀
Are you crazy?
我吃奶的时候 就交会员费了
I started paying my dues when I'm still on the bottle.
甚么鬼屁龙尾棍 听都没听过
I have never heard of such a thing.
你不如说去找魔戒
Why not the One Ring?
是不是连长辈的话也不听 没大没小
You're out of line show some respect for the elders.
论辈份 我还算你的长辈呢
Elders? That's what I am to you.
这么大声跟我说话
Don't raise your voice with me.
臭嫉子 你吸毒吸疯了吧
Dope screwed your brains, bitch?
我懒得跟你废话
I'm not talking to you.
我现在回家
I'm going home
弄个虎鞭汤给我宝贝儿子喝
and make soup for my Baby.
回家吸多点吧 你还不够疯啊
Keep sucking it in, junkie. You're not wasted enough.
打椿机 现在还有人争当坐馆吗
Rammer, people still fight to be the Don these days?
当然有
Of course.
当坐馆能号令天下 多威风呀
It's cool to give out orders.
要死多少人
How many will die?
二三十吧
20 or 30.
花多少钱
How much will it cost?
要三 四百万
$3 or $4 millions.
那还要争
What's the point?
文哥
Swallow.
老大这位子是你应得的
You deserved it.
如果是应得的 那就不用抢了
If I do, there's no need to fight.
现在是查叔那帮人 不讲信义
Only because Uncle Tsa went back on his word.
我们要讨回公道 就要抢
We want justice.
机仔 我入狱后认识了一位前辈
I met a veteran in jail.
他跟我说过
He told me,
最大的过错就是用动机来衡量结果
one of the great mistakes is to judge policies and programs
人们从来不理那些后果的严重性
by their intentions rather than their results.
大哥 你能不能说我听得懂的话
Boss. Can you say that in Cantonese?
我们的社会里 最错的事
The stupidest thing to do
就是不计后果
is to judge something by the motive
只用背后的动机来衡量对与错
and not the result.
太深奥了
That's deep.
这位前辈的辈份一定很高
This guy must be well respected.
他是哪路的
Where is he from?
芝加哥经济学派
Chicago School of Economics.
佛利民
Milton Friedman.
Milton Friedman?
老妈
Mom.
宝贝儿子
My Baby.
宝贝儿子呀
妈对不起你 让你受这么大委屈
I'm sorry you had to suffer.
不是妈 是我对不起你
I'm sorry, Mom.
我混蛋 我不孝
I'm an unfilial asshole.
傻瓜
Don't be silly.
你为社团做事 就是为祖先做事
You work for the Gang and your ancestors.
为祖先做事就是孝 你这么孝义
That makes you a filial son.
妈在尖沙嘴包了个夜场
I booked a place for you in Tsimshatsui East.
全场美女都归你
You can pick any chicks there.
来给祖先上个香
Here, burn incense for your ancestors.
让祖先保佑你夺回坐馆的位子
Pray that they'll help you fight for the Don.
老妈
Mom.
我没时间当坐馆
I won't have time to run the Gang.
我报了香港大学 经济系
I have applied to HKU to study economics.
儿子
My Baby.
你说甚么鬼话呀
You speak English?
你是不是在里面被老外搞了
You screwed around with a foreigner inside?
不是 鸭梨姐
No.
大哥在里面认识一个叫佛利民的前辈
Swallow met someone called Milton Friedman.
给我闭嘴
Shut up.
佛利民是一位经济学家
Friedman is an economist.
我高考成绩有三个优
I earned 3 credits in the A Level exam.
过几天我去大学面试
I'm having an interview in a few days.
坐牢时我想清楚了
I figured it out when I was in jail.
我只想读书
I want to study.
混帐
Nonsense.
你不干黑社会去读书
You can't give up the Gang.
不怕天打雷劈呀
You'll be struck by thunder.
我怎么会被雷劈
Why?
老妈 我去上大学
You're not happy
你不高兴吗
I'm going to college?
对呀
You're right.
我怎么做母亲的
Some mother I am.
我错怪你了 乖儿子
I'm sorry, Baby.
进香港大学招兵买马 这个你都想得出来 太棒了
Recruiting from the university is brilliant.
将来甚么高官 律师
The future top officials and lawyers
全是我们和义盛的人啦
will all be working for the Gang.
东涌仔 快拿蓝精灵来给我镇定一下
Sedate me with some Ectasy now.
乐死我啦乖儿子
I'm so happy, son.
老妈
Mom.
吸吸 你就是吸这些东西
Go ahead.
才弄得疯疯癫癫的
This stuff is making you crazy.
你没听清楚吗我去读书
Did you hear me? I'm going to college.
不是去招兵买马当坐馆
I'm not recruiting new members.
混蛋
Brat.
你不当老大不干黑社会
If you're not the Don
谁供我吸毒
you'll cut off my supply.
你是不是想整死老妈
Are you trying to kill me?
你趁早把它戒了
You should quit.
我趁早弄死我自己
I'd rather kill myself first.
东浦仔给我捡起来
Pick that up, Tung.
不许捡
Stop.
捡起来
Pick them up.
我说不许捡
I said no.
捡起来
Pick them up.
我说不许捡
I said no.
你们谁再让我妈吸毒 我就干掉谁
I'll kill whoever gives her drugs.
听见没有
Understand?
混蛋 你出世起那天就是黑社会
You were born into the Gang.
你一辈子都是黑社会 没得选择
You'll always be in the Gang. You have no choice.
我读过一本书
I read a book
叫 "选择的自由"
called "The Freedom of Choice".
我有选择
I have a choice.
你们都有得选择
We all have a choice.
没事的话 我回房间温习
If there's nothing else, I'll be reading in my room.
天助我也
God is on my side.
竟然杀出个甚么燕子文
He gave me Swallow.
干杯干杯
Cheers. Cheers.
真的要干一杯
We really should drink up.
嫂子
Nancy.
大哥
Boss.
真是天助我也
God is on my side.
燕子文坐牢坐傻了
Swallow screwed up his brain in jail.
说要考大学 不肯当坐馆
He wants to go to college instead.
那枝龙尾棍
The Dragon Tail Baton?
查叔他乱说的
Uncle Tsa made that up.
哪有甚么龙尾棍 随便找一根就行了
There's no such thing. Just make it up.
那也不能太随便吧 大哥
You can't be too casual.
你又搞甚么花样
What are you up to?
我 我能搞得甚么呀 大哥
What else can I... do?
火脯
Roast Pork.
大哥知道你担心甚么
I know what you're thinking.
我一定会罩住你
I'll watch over you.
这帮小弟会二十四小时全天候保护你
My boys will protect you round the clock
直到你当上坐馆为止
until you become the Don.
好啊
Very well.
你也知道
Just to ensure.
我是怕有人从中作梗
No one gets in the way
对 对
Right.
吃饭啦 嫂子 都凉了
Let's eat before the food gets cold.
怎么搞的
What the hell?
半路杀出个燕子文 我岂不是又要等
Who's this Swallow? I have to wait again?
没关系大哥
It doesn't matter, Boss.
等你当上坐馆
If you become the Don...
你就没时间修指甲了
You won't time to do your nails.
大哥
Well.
要涂甚么颜色
What pattern do you like?
晶亮油
Lacquer?
师傅说我最近欠火
The Master said the color red would be good for me.
桃红色加水晶
Red with diamonds.
干甚么
What?
买菜刀呀
You want a knife?
聊两句吗
May I have a word?
你说话呀
Speak up.
让我站一会行吗
Let me just stand for a while.
站够了没有 有话快说
Hurry up and spit it out.
老实说 伟哥
I'll be honest with you, Scissors.
火脯哥呢 他心中有数
Roast Pork knows his limits.
坐馆这位子他没本事
He's not cut out to be the Don.
但伟哥你就不一样 你是兵器世家呀
But you're different. You come from a family of weapons.
你不坐就太可惜了
It's such a shame if you don't make it.
所以 给你出了个好主意
I have an idea.
只要你能够让燕子文进大学
If Swallow is accepted into the University,
到时 坐馆这位子除了你
You'll be the Don.
谁还有资格啊
No one else is qualified.
你用得着这么大声吗
You don't haνe to raise your voice.
我怕你听不见嘛
I want to make sure you heard me.
明天九点 是九点
Tomorrow morning at 9,
燕子文会在港大 是港大
Swallow will be at HKU... it's HKU
他去那里面试 你该知道怎样做吧
for an interview, you know what to do.
怎么回事
What happened?
好像撞到条狗吧
They... ran over a dog.
甚么狗
What dog?
混蛋 你怎么过马路的
Watch where you're going, asshole.
刘长官
Inspector Lau.
有情报
I have intel
可不可以先帮我 叫救护车
but can you get me... an ambulance first?
拜托
Thank you.
你们三个不怕你大哥杀了你们
Swallow said he'd kill you.
这二十年
For the past 20 years, thanks to you
要不是鸭梨姐你啊 我们早就没命了
our lives have been spared.
就是 我们一直把你当亲妈妈
You're like our mother.
大哥去了图书馆温习
Swallow is at the library.
这顿就抽饱点
Enjoy this while you can.
那臭小子能像你们三个这么懂事就好了
It'd be great if he's sensible like you.
鸭梨姐 文哥明天去港大面试
He has an interview at HKU tomorrow.
是吗
Really?
看我明天怎样教儿子
Watch me teach him a lesson.
麻烦你
Thank you.
有句话说
There's a saying:
当市场出现垄断的时候
When there's monopoly in the market,
市场就会产生毁灭自身的机制
the market will kick off a self destructiνe mechanism.
我们大学本着有教无类的精神
The University is open to all students
但是今天来了一帮人
but a gang of people
打走所有考生 还把我打成猪头一样
scared off the students, beat me up
更逼我们一定要录取你
and forced me to admit you.
你连 "垄断只会带来毁灭" 都不懂
If you don't understand "monopoly brings destruction",
叫我怎么录取你 王子文
how can I admit you, Swallow?
不是呀 教授
But Professor...
你别动
Don't move.
别以为我戴眼镜的就好欺负
Don't think I won't hit back because I wear glasses.
我是国术学会的顾问
I'm the consultant of the Martial Arts Club.
给我打 打到他们肯录取他为止
Beat them up until they admit him.
救命啊 救命啊
Help...
给我站住
Stop.
妈 你干甚么呀
What are you doing, Mom?
宝贝儿子
Baby.
一直以来 哪次妈不撑你
I always back you up.
你想读书是吗
You want to go to school?
这次妈就撑你
I'm behind you all the way.
谁敢阻挡就谁死
Whoever gets in my way will die.
谁给胆子你们三个 跟我妈一起疯
Where did you get the nerve to mess around with my Mom?
我们没疯 我们是为大哥做事
We're doing this for you.
我们是为大哥做事
We're on your side.
救命啊救命啊
Help.
给我打 救命啊
Fix them
打到他们肯录取燕子文为止
until he admits Swallow.
警察 警察 别动
Police. Stop it. Take it easy.
把东西放下 把东西放下
Stop it.
老婆
Honey.
糟了
It's terrible.
香港大学校长刚刚宣布 永不录取燕子文
The dean of HKU just announced they'd never admit Swallow.
那孩子们不就可以进名校了
Then our kids can go to an elite school?
当然啦
Of course.
老公
Honey.
干嘛
What?
厨房出事了
There's a situation in the restaurant.
大哥 二十多桌的顾客
Customers at 20 tables
吃了我们的义盛全餐后 喊肚子痛
showed signs of food poisoning.
已经报了警 警察快到了
The Police will be here soon.
有色的
Green?
孔雀石绿
Malachite green.
流鼻涕 禽流感
Snot? Bird flu.
大哥这边还有呀
Over here, Boss.
墨西哥猪肉 猪流感
Mexican pork? Swine flu.
谁害我 谁害我
Who set me up?
警察和卫生帮都到楼下了
The cops and hygiene inspectors are downstairs.
怎么办
What now? I don't know.
倒 扔 埋
Toss and hide.
我先出去摆平顾客
I'll deal with the customers.
快点快点快点倒掉帮忙
Get rid of it. Hurry. Give him a hand. Giνe it here.
快点 快点 小心呀
Hurry. Be careful, moron.
全部倒掉 快点 全部倒掉 全部
Throw it out in the alley.
这种菜 狗都不吃啊
Even dogs won't eat this shit.
这些 是文哥给你当坐馆的贺礼
All this... courtesy of Swallow.
你再说一次
Say that again.
喂 喂
Hey... Hey.
你们和义盛在搞甚么鬼
What's going on?
我在问你呀
I'm asking you.
我让你再说一次
I dare you to repeat it.
你是不是当我透明呀
Am I transparent to you?
一届
One term.
当是为了妈 就做一届吧
Do it for me. Just one term.
最多做完之后
When the term is up,
你爱读甚么就读甚么
you can study anything you want.
要我戒甚么就戒甚么
I'll quit anything you want me to quit.
一届
One term.
就当为了我 只一届坐馆
Do this for me.
以后你想做甚么都行
You can do anything you want.
听说争坐馆的那个
I heard my competitor is...
是个厨师对吧
a chef?
现在人家都踩到头上了
He's stepping on your toes.
你以为能躲得了吗
You can't run away.
阿仁
Yan.
这个警察好面熟呀
The cop looks familiar.
好像我的人呀
Is he one of mine?
十五分钟后给我摆平
You have 15 minutes to settle this
否则的话 你们和义盛桑拿夜总会
or else all your hooker joints, night clubs,
赌船 泊车档 药房和烟馆
casinos, valet parking, drug stores and canteens
准备全给我拆招牌 懂吗
will close down. You hear me?
和义盛
The name of the Gang is Wo Yee Sing
以"和"为贵 以"义"为先 以为"盛"世
which stands for "peace loyalty and prosperity".
这三个字就因为有些人吃古不化
Because some people are a stick-in-the-mud,
才弄到今天这样不三不四
the name is now neither here nor there.
甚么不三不四
What do you mean?
这三个字是我爷爷和几位开山祖师
My Grandpa and other founding fathers used this name
在油麻地卖假首饰骗南洋华侨的店名
for the shop in Yaumatei to sell fake jewelry.
商业登记也是买回来的
They bribed the government for the business license.
白痴 以和为贵
Peace? Don't make me laugh.
你没文化 我懒得理你
That's because you're uncivilized.
火脯 还不告诉人家
Tell them, Roast Pork,
有哪几家殡仪馆是我小兄弟开的
which funeral homes belong to my brother.
顺便派几张柴湾坟场
Give them a business card
那几家墓埠店的名片给他们
of the tombstone shop in Chai Wan,
免得人家来不及预订 要横尸街头
in case they die before they have time to order one.
宝贝儿子 给我数清楚人头
Baby, give me a headcount
到时要送花圈帛金
so I'll send enough wreaths.
当坐馆的 这些礼是少不了的
As the Don, you must not be stingy or people will talk.
别让人说闲话 一人少一句行不行啊
Stop arguing.
在人家的地方还狗咬狗的
We're in a Police station.
多没面子
This is so embarrassing.
都说了谁找回龙尾棍 就谁当坐馆嘛
It's decided whoever finds the Dragon Tail Baton will be the Don.
好 你说的
Fine. You said it.
找到龙尾棍就是坐馆
Whoever finds it will be the Don.
表示人人都有机会
It's fair game.
民主万岁 还政于民
Long live democracy.
甚么龙尾棍呀 甚么样子
Dragon Tail Baton? What does it look like?
龙尾棍上面 有你爷爷
It has your Grandfather
和义盛开山祖师大刀王五的签名
the Iron Bodyguard's signature.
你搞的
You did this?
你怎么搞 我也怎么搞
I'm doing what he's doing.
你搞得我不爽
If I'm not happy
我就搞你全家
it's your family's ass.
你说甚么
What did you say?
听不明白
You don't get it?
搞你 全家
Your... family's... ass.
这么说 我也可以搞你的亲人
So I can screw your mother?
你能吗
Can you?
好啊
Very well.
八月十五 我拿龙尾棍去香堂祭祖的时候
On August 15, when I hold the Baton and offer incense,
我当上坐馆 别说搞你亲人
I'll be the Don. Your mother is not the only one.
你敢转身 我连你都搞了
I might come after you too.
真的吗
Is that a promise?
要看谁的手腕够硬
We'll see who has the balls.
要是想缩 记得通知
Let me know if you cop out.
老公
Honey.
我想看看孩子
I want to check on the kids.
我要练功
I'm practicing.
别烦我
Don't bother me.
喂
Hello?
大哥
Boss.
怎么样
Well?
小心 这凳子不能坐
Don't sit on it.
这样子是光绪年的东西了
This stool is from the period 1875-1908,
差不多是大刀王五那时候
about the time of the Iron Bodyguard.
我那个大刀王五是戴麟趾的年代呀
I only know Chang Cheh's Iron Bodyguard.
大哥
Boss.
虽然是假的
It's a fake
但也要假得像真的才行
but it must look like the real thing.
谢谢
Thanks.
就算是 也不用几万块吧
Still, you paid a fortune.
我的
That's mine.
干嘛给我
Why give it to me?
燕子文召集了上千人
Swallow summoned over 1,000 men who are well paid.
全都收了安家费
They want the Baton and our asses.
矛头直指我和你的那支棍
I'll be the bait.
等一会 我做饵去引开他
Take this on the boat.
你带这支棍上船
You'll be in danger.
那你不是很危险
Boss.
大哥
You want me to be the Don.
是你要我当这个坐馆
This is a match of a lifetime.
这场球赛有今生没来世
You don't want it to go to into over time with penalty kicks.
你也不想加时再踢点球吧
My man.
好兄弟
The back door is that way.
后门那边
Be careful.
小心啊
Kill him.
砍他 砍他
Hurry.
去哪里 尿急啊
Don't piss around here.
混蛋
Asshole.
你给我听清楚 我只说一次
Listen good, I'll say this once.
三十四号线去铜锣湾
34A to Causeway Bay.
三十五号线去湾仔
34B to Wanchai.
对 是湾仔
It's Wanchai.
湾仔
Wanchai?
就在铜锣湾附近嘛
Next to Causeway Bay.
铜锣湾
Causeway Bay?
铜锣湾就在湾仔隔壁
Causeway Bay is next to Wanchai.
碎一点 砍呀
Chop it up nicely.
再剁碎一点
Do it.
手指头 不要啦
Your fingers. You don't want them?
给 拿着
Hold them.
停下 帮我找找我的手指头
Stop. Help me find my finger.
调头
Turn around.
大哥你看后面呀
Behind you.
拿棍下车
Take the Baton.
留下龙尾棍
Drop the Baton.
龙尾棍 龙尾棍 龙尾棍...
Dragon Tail Baton...
走
Run.
大哥 你没事吧
Are you alright?
走
Split.
警方相信
The Police believe the murder
事件与三合会组织和义盛有关
is triad related.
已经拘捕超过四十名
Over 40 suspects
涉嫌一连串殴斗案件的疑犯
related to the incident have been arrested.
警务处长 早前发出声明
The Police Commissioner
表示对事件十分关注
has expressed his concern.
这么严重
That's serious.
要不要躲一躲
Should we go into hiding?
对 走
Let's go.
老妈
Mom.
宝贝儿子 宝贝儿子呀
My Baby.
龙尾棍呀
Dragon Tail Baton.
还不过来扶新任坐馆
Give the new Don a hand.
儿子 你没事吧 等等
Are you alright? Hold it.
你们要的龙尾棍
Dragon Tail Baton...
我也有
I have the Baton too.
大哥 怎么了大哥
Boss...
痛啊
It hurts.
我给你看
Look, Boss.
你看 这根是真的
This is the real thing.
龙尾棍
Dragon Tail Baton.
老查 只有你见过龙尾棍
Tsa, you're the only one who has seen it.
快验一下 哪根是真 哪根是假
Check it out, which one is real?
就两根棍子 要验这么久
What's taking so long?
外形来的 还要研究
What's there to look at?
多验也没坏处
I need a good look
几十年前的事 谁记得清楚 就是
It was decades ago, who'd remember?
你的眼镜不清楚
You need new glasses?
谢谢
Thanks.
不客气
You're welcome.
说实话 这两枝棍 真与假重要吗
Those batons. Who cares if they're real?
不重要
You're right.
出来混 谁的拳头够硬
Let the fist decide.
那才是最重要的
That's more important.
江湖规矩
We'll do it the old way.
单挑
One on one.
宝贝儿子呀
Baby.
不要 不要 不要 不要呀
No...
怎么走
Which way?
左转
Turn left.
现在去哪里
Where are we going?
我说左转呀 大哥
I said left.
我不是左转了吗
I turned left.
这边才是左嘛
This is left.
你说清楚点 我以为你是说我的左
I thought you meant my left.
你的左跟我的左不都一样吗
Your left is the same as my left.
怎么会一样 你看后视镜
No it's not, look in the rear view mirror.
这个是左 这个也是左 小心有狗
This is left, this is also left. Watch out for the dog.
大哥 不是狗
It's not a dog, Boss.
有块猪肝
Pig's liver?
大哥
Boss...
大刀王五
Iron Bodyguard.
香港制造
Made in Hong Kong.
很明显 我大哥的这根 才是真货
Obviously, we have the real thing.
宣布吧 随便吧 警察快到啦
Make the announcement. Suit yourself, the cops are coming.
我现在宣布
I proclaim Scissors
和义盛的新任坐馆是剪刀伟 走吧
is the new Don of the Gang. Let's go.
我要谢谢我的爸爸妈妈
I want to thank my Mom and Dad
多年来支持我做黑社会
for their long time support,
还有我姑妈 带我去看 "英雄本色"
my aunt who took me to see "A Better Tomorrow",
还有 "古惑仔" 的大导演
and Andrew Lau
刘伟强
who directed "Young and Dangerous".
快走吧 警察就到啦 别磨蹭了
The cops are coming.
老妈
Mom.
老妈 快醒醒
Wake up, Mom.
打椿机那混蛋 给我吸甚么了
What did Rammer giνe me?
我是不是傻了 我是不是傻了
Have I gone nuts?
你没傻 是我和火脯合谋的
You're fine. Roast Pork and I planned this.
要想缩 记得通知
Let me know if you cop out.
儿子 这张纸写的是甚么
What's this, son?
这个啊
This one?
MSM
MSM?
小鸡 还认不认得我
Remember me, Chicken?
这鸡是你的
Is that your chicken?
这刀是你的
Is that your blade?
你厨艺这么好 干嘛加入黑社会
You're a good cook, why join the triad?
为了家
For my family.
你呢
And you?
为我妈
For my Mom.
你妈被人搞
Someone messed with her?
我搞你全家
Mess my ass.
是你这个王八蛋
You asshole.
当着孩子说什么呢 教坏孩子
Watch your mouth. Not in front of the kids.
我全家 打个招呼
This is my family, say hello.
你好
Hello.
这三个是反应位
This is your position.
紫色的是我的
Purple is mine.
出租车就在这个位置
The taxi is here.
上面那条街还是下面那条
The street above or below?
走
Let's go.
你们慢慢聊
Take your time.
宝贝儿子呀
Baby.
你不想当坐馆就告诉老妈呀
If you don't want the job, just tell me.
刚才吓死妈了
You scared me to death.
老妈 我说过很多次啦 你就是不听
I did, but you won't listen.
我听不见 你就说到我听见为止嘛
Keep telling me until I hear you.
你当然听不见
Of course you can't hear me.
吸食毒品 会产生幻听
The drugs screwed up your hearing.
行啦 听见啦
I can hear you now.
吸毒者的肾脏
Drugs will shrink your kidneys
会收缩到像乒乓球那么小
to the size of a ping-pong.
知道啦 严重的会影响性能力
I know. Affect your sex.
行啦 我戒啦 倾家荡产 妻离子散
Alright, I'll quit. Cost you your fortune, break up the family.
行 行啦 你戒不戒
Alright. Will you quit?
都说了我戒啦 你比我妈还罗嗦
I said I would. Don't be a nag.
你是不是真的戒
Are you serious?
感谢主
Thank the Lord.
你信教了
You have converted?
你也跟我一起
You should too.
妈 明天跟我去聚会
Come to the fellowship with me tomorrow.
甚么聚会
What's that?
没甚么
A social gathering
就像平时跟社团老头们聚会一样
just like the Gang.
谢谢
Thank you.
文哥
Swallow.
接下来有甚么打算
What's your plan?
我坐牢时认识了一位前辈 他跟我说
A veteran I met in jail told me,
狼行天下 吃肉
a wolf in charge eats meat;
狗行天下 吃屎
a dog in charge eats shit.
你想吃屎还是吃肉
You want to eat meat or shit?
我想做个人
I want to be a person.
其实我认识你的那天
The day I met you,
已经是这样想了
that's what I had in mind.
真的
Really?
好大
Cool?
你妈给你吃什么了
How did your Mom raise you?
警察查牌
Police.
查甚么牌 没见过黑社会缥妓呀
Why? Triad members are entitled to whoring.
阿仁 你也被抓起来了
Yan, they arrested you too?
对不起 我是警察
Sorry, Police.
给我站好了 男左女右
Men on the left, women on right.
身份证 你给我名片干嘛
I want your I.D. Card, not your business card.
对他好一点
Go easy on him.
他是白痴
He's retarded.